kuoni.co.uk 2018-03-30

# Privacy Policy - Kuoni Travel

The copyright in the material on this web site rests with Der Touristik UK Ltd and its suppliers.

Your access to it does not imply a licence to reproduce and/or distribute this information. This means that you cannot reproduce or distribute this information. 

This website is governed and construed in accordance with the Laws of England and is subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the English Courts.

We respect the privacy of our customers therefore we are committed to the following privacy policy, which is designed to give you peace of mind and confidence.

### What personal information do we ask for?

Whether you are booking a holiday, requesting a brochure, or joining our Online Travel Club, we will ask for your name, your postal address, your telephone and fax number and e-mail address.

If you are booking your holiday online, we'll also need your credit/debit card details (including card number, cardholder name, expiry date and start date for Mastercard) in order to take payment and confirm the booking on-line. If you're paying by debit card we may also need to take the start date and issue number of the card.

### How does Kuoni use this personal information?

#### Brochure requests & online travel club:

We need your name, address and/or e-mail address so that we can send out your brochure order, and/or advise you of special offers/promotions we think you would be interested in. On all forms you will be given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving occasional marketing information from Kuoni.

**If your name or contact details have changed, please send your new contact details to:[aftersales@kuoni.co.uk](mailto:aftersales@kuoni.co.uk).**

**If you no longer want to receive Kuoni marketing information, please click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of our emails, or send your customer reference, full address and email to  [changes@kuoni.co.uk](mailto:changes@kuoni.co.uk).**

#### Online Bookings:

We need your name so we can confirm these details to the relevant hotels, airlines etc. who the booking is for.

We also need your address so that we can send you a confirmation invoice as well as your travel documents and in case we have to write to you about any part of your booking in advance of your holiday.

We would need your telephone number and e-mail address in the unlikely event that we need to contact you urgently about your booking.

We may also use this information to let you know about any special offers/promotions we think would be of interest to you.

You will be given the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such information on the booking form.

We may also use your IP (Internet Protocol) address to diagnose problems with our server and administer the site - monitoring visitor traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop and improve the Kuoni site further.

We need your credit card details so that we can collect payment for your booking.

Information you supply to us will be passed to our suppliers (such as airlines, hotels, transport companies) and agents only where necessary for the purposes of booking your holiday. This may include the transfer of information outside the EEA (European Economic Area).

Read More

### Will Kuoni disclose any of this personal information to third parties?

Kuoni will only disclose your name and booking details/holiday proposal to our suppliers for operational purposes. We will not pass on your details to other companies for marketing purposes.

We won't disclose credit/debit card numbers unless we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

### How does Kuoni protect customer information? 

All the information you give us is protected by a secure server. The secure server software SSL (Secure Socket Layers) encrypts all information you enter before it is sent to us. The information is only de-encrypted when it reaches our server.

We also have a Firewall (security software) in place to protect our internal information from the Internet.

Kuoni use cookies on our website for a variety of reasons. We want our website to be as informative, personal, and user friendly as possible and cookies help us to achieve that goal.

Please note that  **no attempts are made to identify individual users, store personal information and cookies cannot harm your computer**.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. Please see information about how to do this below however this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

### What is a cookie

A cookie is a simple, tiny text file that is stored on a web browser when you visit a website that is incapable of performing any tasks or functions. When you revisit a web page, your browser checks to see if any cookies that are stored on your computer are valid ones for the page you are visiting. If they are, the information contained within them is sent back to that webserver.

Without cookies, you could visit two web pages and the website would not connect that you have seen both pages. It would look at the visits individually. Cookies will allow you to book a holiday online, contribute to a gift list or remember which hotel or resort you are searching for on a specific date to check availability and price. Kuoni uses cookies mainly because they make the browsing experience more efficient, enjoyable and provide relevant content.

### Are cookies dangerous?

No. Cookies are small pieces of text. It is not a program, cannot be used as a virus or access your hard drive, and no other website can use it. Your browser will only share information in the cookie from the website that provided it.

Modern browsers allow users to set their own limitations to the number of cookies saved on their hard drives. To learn more about cookies, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Why do Kuoni use cookies?

Cookies let us identify the device you are using and how you use our website – but not you personally. They are essential for many features of our website to work, help us identify and resolve errors, monitor web traffic and identify which pages are being used to help us analyse data and improve our site. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and they in no way give us any information about you.

Kuoni’s cookies’ key features allow you to:

•   Store and review favourite items added to your ‘Travel Planner’ from whichever device you choose.

•   Check live price and availability, purchase a holiday, order a brochure or contribute/view your Kuoni Gift List.

•   Collect information and surveys so Kuoni can learn more about how you use our website and improve your online experience.

•   Provide you with relevant prices and offers on our own website and through our marketing activity.

•   Allow you to share holidays you are interested in among your choice of social media channels

Kuoni has good relationships with a small number of carefully selected suppliers who may also set cookies on behalf of us in order to improve our website and bring our customers information and offers that are relevant to you. If you would like more information about the cookies used by these suppliers, please see below.

Cookies cannot harm your computer and Kuoni will not use cookies to collect personally identifiable information about you.

Read More

### How to modify your browser settings to decline cookies

### Will Kuoni use the information I give for direct mailings?

Yes, but only on a small scale and we try to make sure they only contain information you wouldn't want to miss! If you find that you'd rather not have any contact with us, apart from that which is necessary for us to give you our normal level of service either use the opt-out boxes on the online registration/booking form or alternatively, please write to us at the address below.

If you have any questions relating to our privacy policy, or, if at any time you believe that Kuoni has not adhered to this privacy policy please let us know by sending an e-mail to [webmaster@kuoni.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@kuoni.co.uk). Alternatively write to us at Marketing, Kuoni, Kuoni House, Deepdene Ave, DORKING, Surrey RH5 4AZ.

## The cookies Kuoni use

### Performance

'Performance' cookies collect information about how you use the Kuoni website, such as which pages you visit and if you experience any errors. Performance cookies don't collect any information that could identify you – all the information collected is anonymous and is only used to help us improve how the Kuoni website works, understand what interests you and measure how effective our advertising is.

**We use performance cookies to:**

  * Gather statistics on how our website is used
  * See how effective our adverts are (we don't use this information to target adverts to you when you visit other websites)
  * Help us improve our website by noting any errors that happen

**Cookies we have defined as 'performance' cookies will NOT be used to:**

  * Gather information that could be used to advertise products or services to you on other websites
  * Remember your preferences or username after your visit to our website
  * Target adverts to you on another website

### Functionality

'Functionality' cookies are used to help you use the Kuoni website, provide services and remember settings to improve your visit.

**We use 'functionality' cookies to:**

  * Remember your preferences, such as departure date, destination or the number of passengers travelling on your holiday
  * Remember if we've already asked you if you want to fill in a survey

Cookies defined as 'functionality' will not be used to:

  * Target you with adverts on other websites

Provider

| 

Purpose

| 

Cookie

| 

Privacy URL  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
Kuoni

| 

This cookies allow Kuoni to identify you as a unique user between pages and remember certain settings you have chosen, like an offer you were interested in or search criteria if you have filled out a form

When you’re contributing to a Kuoni Gift List or booking a holiday, we need to use cookies to keep track of what you’re booking as you move through different pages in the booking process.

| 

hotelcal  dynsearch tcksession Bookdetails ASP.NET_SessionId

| 

n/a  
  
Kuoni

| 

In order to request brochures by post or email, Kuoni requires the use of a cookie. Where personal information is stored, this is confidential to Kuoni and is not shared with a third party

| 

brochure_families brochure_sel

| 

n/a  
  
Kuoni

| 

We use this cookie to store your favourite items on our site so you can compare products or request an email quote. It also allows you to be automatically signed in to the Kuoni Travel Planner, which you have previously registered for.

| 

MyPage'   mykuoni-remembered

| 

n/a  
  
Show Cookies

### Targeting

'Targeting' cookies are linked to services provided by third parties, such as 'Like' buttons and 'Share' buttons. The third party provides these services in return for recognising that you have visited our website.

We use 'targeting' cookies to:

  * Link to social networks like Facebook, who may subsequently use information about your visit to target advertising to you on other websites
  * Measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns so we can bring you the most relevant holiday offers possible and limit the number of times an ad is shown to you

Provider

| 

Purpose

| 

Cookie

| 

Privacy URL  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
kuoni.co.uk

| 

Used by our affiliate partners to track referrals and sales related to these targeting cookies. They are also used in order to compensate affiliates 

| 

_aw_m_3353 affiliate

|   
  
Doubleclick (Google)

| 

Floodlight Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns,provide a mechanism to serve partner tags, and allow ads to be served with more relevant messaging based on pages you visit on this site

| 

Channel ID, id

| 

Google

| 

DNS Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns through the identification of organic search click visitors

| 

Channel ID, NID, PREF

| 

Mojn

| 

Mojn "tags" visitors to its partners' websites with browser cookies. Users tagged by Mojn are given a technical identifier. At no point does Mojn collect identifying personal data such as your name or address.  
The browser cookies track the products viewed by the visitor and pages visited of the partner for whom Mojn is delivering ads. Pixel tags are used by Mojn to transfer browsing data from visitors of our partner's websites to Mojn's servers. 

| 

idt rtt rtttmp

| 

Quantcast

| 

Retargeting Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns so we can provide relevant and tailored offers to our customers based on their previous search history.

| 

d, mc

| 

RadiumOne

| 

Retargeting Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns so we can provide relevant and tailored offers to our customers based on their previous search history.

| 

RA1balancer, ra1_sgm, ra1_sid, ra1_uid

| 

GroupM

| 

Retargeting Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns so we can provide relevant and tailored offers to our customers based on their previous search history.

| 

OAX, id, mdata

| 

Facebook

| 

Retargeting Tags are used to measure the effectiveness of online marketing campaigns so we can provide relevant and tailored offers to our customers based on their previous search history.

| 

datr, lu, fr

| 

Show Cookies

### Social media

We offer a share page widget on all of our web pages for Facebook, Twitter and Google+. This allows you to easily share holidays or travel related information that you are interested in with your friends, family and social networks.

These sites may set a cookie when you are logged into their services. Kuoni has no control or liability over these cookies set, so you should check with the relevant third party’s cookie policy for more information.
